<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on chenbrian</title>
    <link>//chenbrian.ca/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on chenbrian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 — Brian Chen — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 15:23:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//chenbrian.ca/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Toggling laptop touchsreen on Wayland</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/wayland_toggle_touchscreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 15:23:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/wayland_toggle_touchscreen/</guid>
      <description>Back when I was still on X11 1 , I had this little bash script to toggle my touchscreen on/off since I didn&amp;rsquo;t use it all that often except to sign the occasional PDF, and it sucked up power2.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14  #!/usr/bin/bash  # toggles touchscreen on x11-based systems isOn=&amp;#34;$(xinput --list-props &amp;#39;SYNA2393:00 06CB:19AC&amp;#39; | grep &amp;#39;Device Enabled&amp;#39;)&amp;#34; isOn=&amp;#34;${isOn: -1}&amp;#34; if [ $isOn -eq 0 ]; then xinput set-prop &amp;#39;SYNA2393:00 06CB:19AC&amp;#39; &amp;#39;Device Enabled&amp;#39; 1 echo &amp;#34;Turning touchscreen on!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>conway&#39;s game of life in 3D w/ three.js</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/conway.3js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:14:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/conway.3js/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back one of my roommates mentioned in passing that they were thinking of writing conway&amp;rsquo;s game of life as a little widget for their website. I thought that was pretty fun and suggested that it would be really neat if it were in 3D as well.
&amp;hellip;Anyways fast-forward about two hours and I was stuck in a 3-hour lecture. So I wrote it (as is pretty evident below)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pi Pico on Linux</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/pi-pico-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 23:08:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/pi-pico-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Needed to use a Pi Pico for one of my courses (which mandated circuitpython &amp;hellip; for reasons unknown) and noticed that Adafruit&amp;rsquo;s documentation for using CircuitPython with something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t Mu Editor was not really up to par.
 Install CircuitPython by copying .uf2 file into the Pi Pico, which can be done by just plugging it into your computer python3 -m pip install circuitpython-stubs to get completions with your LSP of choice Connect to serial port to view prints and logging info   find the appropriate port with ls /dev/ttyACM* connect using GNU screen or whatever you like to use  e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a resume with LaTeX</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/latex-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:31:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/latex-resume/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it &amp;ndash; \( \LaTeX \)) is unequivocally cooler than Word. And you want an unequivocally cool resume as well.
So you tried altacv, but it always got absolutely chewed up by ATS systems.
And so you yearned for a 🌠cool🥶 single-column layout, but you couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one.
I present: my fork of altacv with a few 🌟 revolutionary 🌟 features.
 Cut down on icons to improve pdf-to-text conversion Change to a single-column layout \itag{asdf} command to draw an inline &amp;ldquo;tag&amp;rdquo; \chref command for hyperlinks Disabling word wrapping and hyphenation Various changes to \makecvevent, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using NeoVim for ROS2 c&#43;&#43; development</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/using-neovim-for-ros2-c-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 04:23:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/using-neovim-for-ros2-c-development/</guid>
      <description>Using clangd ROS2 puts its headers into a rather non-standard location, /opt/ros2/&amp;lt;ROS_DISTRO&amp;gt;/include. Obviously this doesn&amp;rsquo;t play well with standard clangd setups, and it would be too easy if it just worked out of the box with vim! Most editors like vscode or clion have their own way of handling scenarios like this, e.g. vscode using a c_cpp_properties.json file.
 For vscode setup, see this or this
 With vim this is as little uglier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on &#39;Clean Architecture: A Craftsman&#39;s Guide to Software Structure and Design&#39;</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/clean-architecture-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 16:39:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/clean-architecture-notes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Fight for the architecture&amp;rdquo;
 The following is a Work in progress collection of notes on &amp;lsquo;Clean Architecture: A Craftsman&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Software Structure and Design&amp;rsquo; by Robert C. Martin. [1]
[1] R. C. Martin, Clean Architecture: A Craftsman’s Guide to Software Structure and Design, 1st ed. USA: Prentice Hall Press, 2017.
Paradigms Main paradigms:
  Structured: Discipline on direct transfer of control
 Dijkstra: banishing the goto statement; enforcing control flow; if, else, while, for &amp;hellip; Enabling functional decomposition; applying mathematical divide-and-conquer approach to algorithms Testing can only prove a program false but not correct  Structured programming breaks down to provable chunks      Object-oriented: Discipline on indirect transfer of control</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:03:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/projects/</guid>
      <description>// Page under construction //
 &amp;ldquo;If you built a project and did not write about it, did you really build a project?&amp;rdquo;
 Overview Browse projects by tag
  GrocerCheck: Github, Pitch Deck A website to help people reduce contact at grocery stores and essential services. Got some press coverage too!
 CBC Piece CBC Piece, but in French CBC TV piece can be found below Daily Hive: Toronto, Vancouver, Seattle Seattle Pi CBM Press (Korean News) Salam Vancouver (Iranian News) Fairchild TV: Interview broadcast on national Chinese TV    aUToronto: Simulation &amp;amp; Testing co-lead, working on automated integration testing &amp;amp; associated ROS/ROS2 tooling Demo below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2021</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/advent-of-code-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 21:20:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/advent-of-code-2021/</guid>
      <description>This page will track some notes and TILs for AoC2021, which I will be completing in rust &amp;ndash; a language I am still learning.
Solutions are hosted here. If a day isn&amp;rsquo;t very interesting, I won&amp;rsquo;t post a writeup for it.
Day 6 Problem Solution
So many lanternfish! The key to this puzzle is to represent the lanternfish as a histogram rather than creating a list of all the lanternfish. See solution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
