<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on chenbrian</title>
    <link>//chenbrian.ca/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on chenbrian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 — Brian Chen — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 17:40:49 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//chenbrian.ca/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Engsci Year 3 Fall</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/engsci-year-3-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 17:40:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/engsci-year-3-fall/</guid>
      <description>This browser does not support PDFs. Please download the PDF to view it: Download PDF.
Or, download here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engsci Year 2 Winter</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/engsci-year-2-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 19:53:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/engsci-year-2-winter/</guid>
      <description>This browser does not support PDFs. Please download the PDF to view it: Download PDF.
Or, download here
Notes prior to reading week can be found below. Right before reading week my roommate introduced me to the NotesTeX template and I&amp;rsquo;m currently using that.
ECE286: Probability and Statistics Probability Coin flip example &amp;amp; combining probabilities Outcomes denoted by variables, i.e. for coin clip \( H \), \( T \). Probability of outcome is denoted by \( P(X) \), where \( X \) is the outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on &#39;Clean Architecture: A Craftsman&#39;s Guide to Software Structure and Design&#39;</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/clean-architecture-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 16:39:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/clean-architecture-notes/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Fight for the architecture&amp;rdquo;
The following is a Work in progress collection of notes on &amp;lsquo;Clean Architecture: A Craftsman&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Software Structure and Design&amp;rsquo; by Robert C. Martin. [1]
[1] R. C. Martin, Clean Architecture: A Craftsman’s Guide to Software Structure and Design, 1st ed. USA: Prentice Hall Press, 2017.
Paradigms Main paradigms:
Structured: Discipline on direct transfer of control
Dijkstra: banishing the goto statement; enforcing control flow; if, else, while, for &amp;hellip; Enabling functional decomposition; applying mathematical divide-and-conquer approach to algorithms Testing can only prove a program false but not correct Structured programming breaks down to provable chunks Object-oriented: Discipline on indirect transfer of control</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 16:49:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/teaching/</guid>
      <description>(Currently) all content is in jupyter notebook format and is hosted on my on GitHub at github.com/ihasdapie/teaching. I&amp;rsquo;ve also set up a binder enviroment so that you can work with them interactively by using clicking on this badge: or following this link mybinder.org/v2/gh/ihasdapie/teaching/HEAD
ESC180 Exam review Jupyter notebook for exam review based on student-requested content. Either download it and run locally, use Google Colab, or this Binder link.
ESC190 Tutorial 1 Tutorial 2 Notes Midterm review (All else currently WIP), see: github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engsci Y2S1 Exam Review</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/engsci-y2s1-exam-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 22:16:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/engsci-y2s1-exam-review/</guid>
      <description>Exam &amp;lsquo;cheat sheets&amp;rsquo; for EngSci 2nd year semester fall semester. These were made as part of my own studying for the exams. As 3/6 of my exams were cancelled due to the omicron covid variant, AER210, MAT292, and PHY293 are missing.
I do not guarantee content correctness &amp;ndash; but if you find a mistake, please let me know!
CHE260 Note: the following only contains materials for the final exam, so it will only cover the heat-transfer portion of CHE260.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
