<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on chenbrian</title>
    <link>//chenbrian.ca/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on chenbrian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021 — Brian Chen — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 19:53:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//chenbrian.ca/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Engsci Year 2 Winter</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/engsci-year-2-winter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 19:53:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/engsci-year-2-winter/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents   TEP 327: Engineering and Law  Resources   ECE286: Probability and Statistics  Lecture 1   ECE259: Electromagnetism     TEP 327: Engineering and Law Why do engineers need to know about law?
 Engineering ends up stepping across a lot of jurisdictions, so we kinda need to know about it.  Law is &amp;hellip;
 very territorial: must note jurisdiction  Must develop intuition for jurisdiction (See section 91) Generally:  Things outside of Canada &amp;amp; maintained across Canada &amp;ndash; Federal Things that are managed within Canada and aren&amp;rsquo;t necessarily consistent (local effect) &amp;ndash; Provincial Things that Provincial gov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 16:49:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/teaching/</guid>
      <description>ESC180 Exam review Jupyter notebook for exam review based on student-requested content. Either download it and run locally, use Google Colab, or this Binder link.
ESC190 // Under construction //
For all else (currently WIP), see: github.com/ihasdapie/teaching/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engsci Y2S1 Exam Review</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/engsci-y2s1-exam-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 22:16:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2021/engsci-y2s1-exam-review/</guid>
      <description>Exam &amp;lsquo;cheat sheets&amp;rsquo; for EngSci 2nd year semester fall semester. These were made as part of my own studying for the exams. As 3/6 of my exams were cancelled due to the omicron covid variant, AER210, MAT292, and PHY293 are missing.
I do not guarantee content correctness &amp;ndash; but if you find a mistake, please let me know!
Table of Contents   CHE260  Variables Heat Transfer Mechanisms Steady Heat Transfer Transient Heat Transfer Forced Convection Heat Transfer Radiation Heat Transfer   ECE253: Digital and Computer Systems  Logic and Circuits Verilog ARM Assembly   MAT292 AER210 PHY293 ESC203     CHE260 Note: the following only contains materials for the final exam, so it will only cover the heat-transfer portion of CHE260.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
