<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on chenbrian</title>
    <link>//chenbrian.ca/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on chenbrian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 — Brian Chen — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:14:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//chenbrian.ca/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>conway.3js</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/conway.3js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:14:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/conway.3js/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back one of my roommates mentioned in passing that they were thinking of writing conway&amp;rsquo;s game of life as a little widget for their website. I thought that was pretty fun and suggested that it would be really neat if it were in 3D as well.
&amp;hellip; anyways fast-forward about two hours and I was stuck in a 3-hour lecture. So I wrote it (as is pretty evident below)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a resume with LaTeX</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/latex-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:31:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/latex-resume/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it &amp;ndash; \( \LaTeX \)) is unequivocally cooler than Word. And you want an unequivocally cool resume as well.
So you tried altacv, but it always got absolutely chewed up by ATS systems.
And so you yearned for a 🌠cool🥶 single-column layout, but you couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one.
I present: my fork of altacv with a few 🌟 revolutionary 🌟 features.
Cut down on icons to improve pdf-to-text conversion Change to a single-column layout \itag{asdf} command to draw an inline &amp;ldquo;tag&amp;rdquo; \chref command for hyperlinks Disabling word wrapping and hyphenation Various changes to \makecvevent, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;The Endless River&#34;, or me, myself, and editing my `init.vim`</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/endless-neovim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 13:35:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/endless-neovim/</guid>
      <description>/* work in progress */
My first text editor was the one used in my highschool intro to cs class, geany &amp;ndash; which is a wonderful lightweight development environment &amp;ndash; and is, in my opinion, an excellent first editor because of its&amp;rsquo; simple yet powerful interface, cross-platform compatibility, and support for most relevant languages.
The Beginning But, at the time, my laptop was a 11.6&amp;quot; chromebook with 16GB of eMMC storage and kitted out with a CPU less capable than most budget modern phones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:03:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/projects/</guid>
      <description>// Page under construction //
&amp;ldquo;If you built a project and did not write about it, did you really build a project?&amp;rdquo;
Overview Browse projects by tag
ROS: Worked on the open-source Robot Operating System (ROS) as a summer intern in 2022. What was really cool about this experience was that I got to work directly with NASA on their VIPER lunar rover project, supporting their use of ROS2 and Gazebo on their simulation, ground control, and autonomy systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(g)o (w)eb (s)erver</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/go-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 20:48:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/go-web-server/</guid>
      <description>Deploying your personal website onto github pages is so 2013. Why avoid the hassle of self-hosting with a static site generator and server? Why not just use something tried and tested by the community?
It&amp;rsquo;s just not as fun &amp;hellip; and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like studying for a final one afternoon.
So here&amp;rsquo;s a simple 111-line golang webserver that you can use to deploy your personal website.
There&amp;rsquo;s also some cute figlet art</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
