<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about_me on chenbrian</title>
    <link>//chenbrian.ca/tags/about_me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about_me on chenbrian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 — Brian Chen — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:31:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//chenbrian.ca/tags/about_me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing a resume with LaTeX</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/latex-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:31:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/2022/latex-resume/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it &amp;ndash; \( \LaTeX \)) is unequivocally cooler than Word. And you want an unequivocally cool resume as well.
So you tried altacv, but it always got absolutely chewed up by ATS systems.
And so you yearned for a 🌠cool🥶 single-column layout, but you couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one.
I present: my fork of altacv with a few 🌟 revolutionary 🌟 features.
 Cut down on icons to improve pdf-to-text conversion Change to a single-column layout \itag{asdf} command to draw an inline &amp;ldquo;tag&amp;rdquo; \chref command for hyperlinks Disabling word wrapping and hyphenation Various changes to \makecvevent, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>What am I up to right now?  Incoming SWE Intern at Open Robotics Software Foundation Systems &amp;amp; Simulations team co-lead @ aUToronto: Automated testing &amp;amp; evaluation of autonomous vehicles, deep learning acceleration with TensorRT, CI/CD, and more! Research @ ISML: I work with accelerating machine learning tasks on memristor crossbars &amp;ndash; first author paper pending submission Web dev &amp;amp; data collection for BC Parks Foundation: currently in private beta Side Projects TA-ing intro programming (ESC180) and data structures &amp;amp; algorithms (ESC190) Trying to make it through university!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi, I&#39;m Brian</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/</guid>
      <description>And I&amp;rsquo;m a student, software developer, and pokemon go enthusiast  &amp;hellip; and let&amp;rsquo;s put a face to the name as well
I&amp;rsquo;m a student at the University of Toronto Engineering Science program passionate about identifying problems in the world around me and creating solutions for them. When I&amp;rsquo;m not cramming for school, I enjoy cooking and playing badminton.
While you&amp;rsquo;re here, why don&amp;rsquo;t you check out my about me page?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
