<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about_me on chenbrian</title>
    <link>//chenbrian.ca/tags/about_me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about_me on chenbrian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2022 — Brian Chen — All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:31:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//chenbrian.ca/tags/about_me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing a resume with LaTeX</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/posts/latex-resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 18:31:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/posts/latex-resume/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s face it &amp;ndash; \( \LaTeX \)) is unequivocally cooler than Word. And you want an unequivocally cool resume as well.
So you tried altacv, but it always got absolutely chewed up by ATS systems.
And so you yearned for a 🌠cool🥶 single-column layout, but you couldn&amp;rsquo;t find one.
I present: my fork of altacv with a few 🌟 revolutionary 🌟 features.
Cut down on icons to improve pdf-to-text conversion Change to a single-column layout \itag{asdf} command to draw an inline &amp;ldquo;tag&amp;rdquo; \chref command for hyperlinks Disabling word wrapping and hyphenation Various changes to \makecvevent, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chenbrian/about</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/about/</guid>
      <description>What am I up to right now? Just wrapped an SWE internship @ Open Source Robotics Foundation Trajectory motion planning sub-team lead @ aUToronto: This year I&amp;rsquo;m working on trajectory motion planning for our vehicles. In previous years I&amp;rsquo;ve led sub-teams for automated testing &amp;amp; evaluation of autonomous vehicles, deep learning acceleration with TensorRT, CI/CD, simulation, and more! TA-ing intro programming (ESC180) and data structures &amp;amp; algorithms (ESC190) Obsessively making pretty notes in \( \LaTeX \) Trying to make it through university!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>chenbrian.ca</title>
      <link>//chenbrian.ca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//chenbrian.ca/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Brian and I&amp;rsquo;m a student, software-engineer-in-training1, and pokemon go enthusiast I&amp;rsquo;m an Engineering Science student at the University of Toronto majoring in Computer Engineering. Outside of school, I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about making cool stuff like self-driving cars, while learning more about the world we live in. When I&amp;rsquo;m not cramming for school, I enjoy cooking and playing badminton.
While you&amp;rsquo;re here, why don&amp;rsquo;t you check out my about me page, or read more about some projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
